ANISH JOHN A

Email: anishj@vjcet.org

Ph:9961734244

Mr. Anish John A works as the Assistant Professor in the Department of Management Studies. He completed his Engineering in Electrical and Electronics and MBA (Marketing) from Dr.GRD College of Science, Coimbatore. He has published various research papers in Peer reviewed and refereed journals including UGC approved journal and has presented research papers in various National and International Conferences.

Educational Qualification

- PhD (Doing in Management) (Bharathiar University, Coimbatore)
- MBA (Marketing) from Dr.GRD College of Science, Coimbatore, Affiliated to Bharathair University, Coimbatore (2010)
- B. E(Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from P.S.N.A College Engineering and Technology, Dindigul.affilated to Anna University, Chennai (2008)

Work Experience

- 2016-2021: Assistant Professor, Department of Commerce and Management, Marygiri College of Arts and Science, Koothattukulam
- 2015-2016: Assistant Professor Department of Management Studies I, Naipunnya School of Management, Cherthala,
- 2013-2015: Assistant Professor, Mar Kuriakose Arts & Science College, Puthuvely
- 2011-2013: Assistant Professor, Al Azhar College of Arts and Science, Thodupuzha
- 2010-2011: Sales Engineer, Rons Enterprises, Gurgaon

Areas of Interest:

Marketing Management, Brand Management & Consumer Behaviour

Publications

- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Factors influencing smartphone purchase intention among generation z", Wesleyan Journal of Research (IJRAR), Volume -14, Issue -1, January, 2021, Page 125-144, ISSN (Print):0975-1386.
- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). Buying Behaviour towards smartphone among generation z", *The Journal of Oriental Research Madras*, *Volume 92, Issue -1, January, 2021, Page 296-312, ISSN(Print) :0022-3301.*

- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Gender difference on factors affecting purchase intention of smartphone among generation z", *International Journal of Research and Analytical Reviews (IJRAR), Volume -5, Issue -8, October-December, 2018, Page 152u-157u, ISSN(Print):2349-5138,*
- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Social factors influencing the smartphone purchase among the generation z", *International Journal of Human Resource Management and Research Volume-8, Issue-5, August-October*, 2018, Page 1-10, ISSN(Print): 2249-6874,
- Anish John A (2015). "The influence of surprise toys on repeat purchase among kids with special reference to kinder joy", International journal of social science and humanities research.vol.3, issue 4 . ISSN 2348-164.
- Anish John A,Sarika &Renju (2015). "Mobile banking in India-Opportunities & Challenges", Finova'15, Green Banking, ISBN 978-93-85105-19-7.
- Anish John A& Sarika (2015). "Preschool Children & Surprise toys" Synernovae '15, ISBN 978-0070682139.

FDP's/Workshops/Seminars/Conference Attended

- Attended FDP on "User Friendly Tools For Online Teaching And Assessment" on 24th
 July to 30th July,2020,organized by Prajyoti Niketan College,Pudukkad.
- Attended two days international webinar on "Emerging business trends post covid 19" on 30&31 August 2020, conducted by Bangalore University associated with Acharya Bangalore B School.
- Attended online workshop on "Art of thesis Writing" organized by Rehoboth Academic Services, Bangalore on 8 August 2020.
- Presented paper in two days Multidisciplinary International Academic research conference (ISBN:9780989515047) on the theme "Buying Behaviour of smartphones among undergraduate students" organized by Anna University-PSGIM-ARC at Coimbatore,18th &19th February 2016.
- Presented paper in one day Multidisciplinary Paper presentation conference on the theme "Pre-School Children and surprise toys" organized by Naipunnya school of Management at Cherthala, 5th December 2015.
- Attended two days workshop on "Research Methodology and Application of Statistical Tools" organized by SCMS Cochin School of Business on June 26th & 27th,2015.

- Conducted by Prof. (Dr.) K. Kalyanaraman (Former Professor &Head, Dept. of Statistics, Kerala University)
- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Methodology and Application of Statistical Tools" on December 5th 2015. Conducted by Dr.R.Gopal (Director,D Y Patil University, Mumbai)
- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Paper writing" on June 1st 2015. Conducted by Dr.Kevin (Former Pro Vice Chancellor, University of Kerala)
- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Methodology and Research Paper writing" on March 3rd 2015. Conducted by Prof. Ajay Saraf (Professor ,Dr.D.Y.Patil University,Mumbai)
- Attended one day Seminar on "Student Counselling and Communication" on October 10th 2015. Conducted by Prof. Jameela P(Principal ,KVM College of special Education,Cherthala)
- Attended FDP, conducted by Minds Training Academy, 1st-5thJune 2015.
- Attended one day Seminar on "Orientation towards NAAC Implementation" on January 1st 2015 Conducted by Dr.Joseph P.X(Professor, Rajagiri College of Social Sciences)